I hate scary movies . I should be
studying . You know I got a bio due .
Baby , did I mention that these tickets were free ?
Free .
Sandra Bullock is playing right down the street .
Nobody wanna pay $ 7.50 to see some Sandra
Bullock shit ... unless she 's naked .
Oh , but you will sit through a movie called Stab ?
It 's adrenaline , Maureen . It 's good to be scared .
It 's primal . You know what I 'm saying ?
No , I 'm going to tell you what it is , okay ?
It 's a dumb-ass white movie about some dumb-ass white girls ...
getting their white asses cut the fuck up , okay ?
Yeah . I suppose Sandra Bullock is Miss Ethnicity , right ?
Well , no , all I 'm saying is that the horror genre is historical ...
for excluding the African-American element .
When the hell you get your PhD In Black Cinema , Sister Souljah ?
Listen , I read my Entertainment Weekly , okay ? I know my shit .
Yeah , Maureen . I read my Black Beat , too , homey .
Tonight we 're going to have an all-black movie ,
all-black cast , all-black wardrobe , black eyes ...
Everything . Black-eyed peas . Black cats ...
- Crazy . - Thank you .
- Hi . Here you go . - What 's this ?
Stab souvenirs . The studio sent them .
Hah . And it 's white .
Thanks .
Thank you .
Kill . Kill . Kill .
Very romantic .
Whoa .
Whoo . Take it off .
Now , why has she got to be naked ?
What does that have to do with the plot
of the story , her being butt-ass naked ?
I don 't know about the plot , but I got a stiff one .
You better loosen up that wrist .
Hello ?
Hello .
- Who is this ? - Guess .
- No , really . Who is this ? - Were you expecting somebody ?
No .
Bitch , hang the phone up and Star-69 his ass . Damn .
Who is this ? Who would you like it to be ?
I don 't like games . Who is this ?
Look out back .
Do you see your boyfriend anywhere ?
I don 't even have a boyfriend right now .
Would you like one ?
Damn it all . Can I ... Give me some money . I need to get some popcorn .
You got money .
I got my money . I asked for your money .
What do you say ?
Cheap ass .
- Thank you . - Come on .
Cat got your tongue ?
You know , I don 't even know you , and I dislike you already .
Come on .
- Hey , we 're sold out . - Oh , cool .
Hello .
Hi . Can I have a medium popcorn , no butter , and a small diet Pepsi ?
- You got it . - Thanks .
That 's it . I am not going back in there .
Come on , you chickenshit . It 's just a movie .
No , it 's not just a movie . It 's a true story .
All these kids got killed a couple years ago in California .
- Here 's the popcorn . - Thanks .
I was so scared , I almost had a heart attack .
Hah . Stab you , man .
Whoa .
- You ass . - I 'm sorry . I had to , baby .
- What are you playing ? - Would you relax ?
God . What 's wrong with you ?
I don 't like being scared . I don 't like that .
Baby , it 's just a movie .
Besides , scary movies are great foreplay .
Excuse me ?
Let 's go see Sandra Bullock .
Oh , no . Sandra started already . We can stay .
Just stop playing so much .
All right . I got to go to the bathroom .
See ya inside .
Sorry .
Hello ?
I didn 't mean it . I didn 't mean it .
I swear . I swear . I 'll be good .
Please , don 't , Mummy .
I 'll tell you . Really . I 'll tell you , Mummy .
Really . I 'll tell you why I did it , Mummy .
Listen , Mummy . Listen , Mummy .
N-N-N-No . No , no , no , no , no , no . Don 't do that .
Move . Move . Go .
Run . Go .
Baby , give it up .
You came back just in time . It looks like she 's about to get it .
Want some popcorn ?
See , if that was me , I would be out of there .
Oh . Here it comes .
Here it comes .
Here it comes . Oh , my God .
Hello ?
- Hello ? - Hello , Sidney .
Yes ?
What 's your favourite scary movie ?
- Who is this ? - You tell me .
Cory Gillis , 555-0176 .
- Oh , shit . - Hot flash , Cory ...
Shit .
Crank calls are a criminal offence ...
prosecuted under penal code 653-M .
Hope you enjoyed the movie .
Time to change numbers again ?
No . It 'll die off .
It 's opening weekend . We 'll see how it goes .
Okay .
You know , Ron , it 's not an easy thing ...
to be accused of a crime you didn 't commit ,
particularly one as heinous as murder .
But how do people treat you now that they
know the truth about your innocence ?
Most people are cool .
There 's some who still keep a safe distance , which is odd for me ,
because I 've always been sort of a people person .
But you were wrongly accused . You were fully exonerated .
Yeah , well , that and a nickel will get you a cup of coffee .
Even that 's not true any more .
Certainly , with Gale Weathers ' book ...
and now the movie ...
it 's set the record straight for Cotton Weary .
One would think . But , Gale 's ... Gale 's been terrific .
Hey . Move your ass , okay ? You 're late .
Don 't forget about that martini mixer
tonight at the Delta Lambda Zetas .
I don 't think I 'm going to be able to make it , Hal .
What ?
Don 't even try to bag , okay ? Because you promised me .
A vague promise at best .
Nobody 's asking you to join , okay ?
It 's a party . Free beer , meet the girls .
Hallie , you know me and organised religion .
- It 's a sorority . - Worse .
Look , Sid , just lower the walls for the next few days .
This self-induced isolation you got going is not healthy .
- I 'm fine . - " I 'm fine . "
Yes , I know . " I 'm fine " is stretched
tightly across your face .
Check out the news .
The two Windsor College students were murdered ...
last night during a sneak preview of the new movie Stab .
Police haven 't released any information
except for the victims ' names ,
but a press conference is scheduled for later today .
The victims , Maureen Evans and Phil Stevens ,
were both Windsor seniors .
Where 's Randy ?
He 's got Film Theory this morning .
Ended with the brutal murders of two promising ...
Sidney . Sidney .
Sidney , did you know the victims ?
Do you feel threatened by the murders ?
No comment .
Do you think there 'll be more murders ?
Sidney . Sidney .
What can you tell us about the victims ?
How about the police ?
- We just need one statement . - Please talk to us .
You could say what happened in that theatre
is a direct result of the movie itself .
That is so Moral Majority . You can 't blame
real-life violence on entertainment .
What ? Wait a second . Yes , you can . Don 't you even watch the news ?
Yeah . Hello . The murderer was wearing a ghost mask , okay ?
Just like in the movie . It 's directly responsible .
No , it 's not . Movies are not responsible for our actions .
It 's a classic case of life imitating art imitating life .
This is not a hypothetical . It 's not about art .
I had Biology with that girl . This is reality .
Thank you . I agree with you . Let me tell you about reality , Mickey .
I lived through this . Okay ?
Life is life . It doesn 't imitate anything .
Come on , Randy , with all due respect ,
the killer obviously patterned
himself after two serial killers ...
who have been immortalised on film .
Thank you .
Are you suggesting that someone 's trying to make a real-life sequel ?
Stab 2 ? Who 'd want to do that ? Sequels suck .
Oh , please . Please .
By definition alone , they 're inferior films .
Bullshit generalisation .
Many sequels have surpassed their original .
- Oh , yeah ? - Name one .
Aliens . Far better than the first .
Yeah , well , there 's no accounting for taste .
Thank you . Ridley Scott rules . Name another .
No . Aliens is a classic , okay ? " Get away from her , you bitch . "
I believe the line is " Stay away from her ,
you bitch . " It 's film class , right ?
Yeah , whatever . You know what I mean .
Another .
T2 .
You 've got a hard-on for Cameron .
- Big one . - Wait a second .
The first Terminator is historical .
Yeah .
" Sarah Connor ? " " Yes . "
All right . All right , okay .
The Second Story .
What ?
The entire horror genre was destroyed by sequels .
Hey , I got it , by the way . I got it .
The Godfather Part II .
Very good . That 's the oscar-winning exception .
All right , that 's enough .
That 'll be a wrap . The sequel discussion to be continued .
So , Mr originality , how would you make it different ?
I 'd let the geek get the girl .
Three hundred people watched . Nobody did anything .
They thought it was a publicity stunt , for Christ 's sakes .
And it would have been a good one too .
- It 's starting again , Randy . - It 's not .
A lot of shit happens at the movies .
People get robbed , shot , maimed , murdered .
Multiplexes are a very dangerous place to be these days .
Yeah , and you are in extreme denial .
And you should be too . This has nothing to do with us .
Randy , a guy in a ghost mask hacked up two people ...
in a movie theatre telling our life story .
Coincidence ?
You know what happened at Woodsboro , Randy .
You can 't ignore it .
I know , Sid , but I don 't want to go back there again .
Can 't we just go back to our pseudo-quasi-happy existence ?
- Hello , Derek . How ya doing ? - Hey , Sid .
- I heard . You weren 't in class . - Yeah , I know .
I skipped . I couldn 't take all the " that 's her " looks .
Is there anything I can do ?
Well , you got any tricks for getting me back ...
to a pseudo-quasi-happy existence ?
- I might just have one for that . - Yeah ?
Oh , yeah ? What is it ?
That was pretty good .
Get a room .
They 're threatening to what ? Are you kidding me ?
They 'd be stupid to pull this movie .
With all this free press , they 're going
to have huge numbers this weekend .
It 'll break box office records .
Consider it done .
Miss Weathers ? Hi . I 'm Joel .
I 'm Joel . The affiliate sent me . I 'm your new cameraman .
- Yeah . You got experience ? - Huh ? Yeah .
I mean , I 'm local , but I shot the bingo finals .
- Great . Great . - I almost got an award for that .
All right , listen , Joel . This is how it works .
I point , you shoot .
You stay focussed and fast on your feet , and we 'll get along fine .
You 're playing with the big boys now , you got it ?
Got it . Got you covered . I 'm all over it .
Don 't worry about a thing . How hard can it be ?
You point and I shoot . I 'm there .
Excuse me , Miss Weathers ? Could I have a minute ?
- No . - Just one second .
I know you probably get this all the time ,
but I just wanted to say I am such a big fan of your work .
I just finished you book . I couldn 't put it down .
Insightful , probing ... I just really , really loved your book .
- Thank you . Thanks . - Sure .
I 'm a writer myself .
I write for the local paper , for the Post Telegram .
I 'm Debbie Salt . I took your seminar in Chicago last year .
I was the one in the front row asking all the questions .
Right . I thought you looked familiar .
Oh , thank you .
Can 't wait to see the movie .
You know , you must be getting quite
a lot of flak on that , right ?
I mean , with all the violence-in-cinema issues .
What is your position going to be ?
No comment .
Miss Weathers , please ... I would ...
It would be such an honour for me if I could
just get a quote from you for my story .
Okay . Begin quote :
Great .
" Your flattering remarks are both desperate and obvious . "
- Ouch . - End quote .
Gale , what are you doing here ? Do you think
these murders are connected to Sidney Prescott ?
Miss Weathers , what 's your feeling about this ?
May I have your attention .
My name is Chief Louis Hartley ...
Chief Hartley .
Hi . Gale Weathers , author of The Woodsboro Murders .
Do you think the killer will strike again ?
We have no evidence that this is a serial killer .
I 'd like to read from a prepared ...
Can you tell us of any precautions that you 're taking ?
Well , first of all , we think it 's just an isolated incident ,
- and we will be ... - Ladies .
Oh , my God . This is huge .
Do you have any suspects ?
Sidney , look . It 's Gale Weathers .
What ?
Star of the Gale Weathers press conference ,
based on the book by Gale Weathers .
Soon to be a major motion picture starring Gale Weathers .
- Be kind . She saved our lives . - She had calf implants .
Chief Hartley , do you plan on giving the town a curfew ?
I 'm going to get closer .
- So that 's her ? - Yeah .
Hello , girls . Enjoying yourselves ?
Hello , Sister Lois , Sister Murphy .
Hello , pledge . Hi , Sidney .
Hey .
This must be flat-out hell for you .
- How are you holding up ? - I manage .
It 's really weird , isn 't it ? To think
this fuss is all because of you .
I mean , not directly , but in some six-degrees-of-Kevin Bacon way .
Now , Hallie , are you going to bring your
friend to our little martini mixer tonight ?
- I have a lot of work to do . - We 'll be there .
Oh , good . Because , Sid , we have our eyes on you .
You hang in there , and if there 's anything we can do ...
The Delta Lambdas are very sensitive to your plight .
- Yeah . Bye . - Bye .
You going to start to dress like that once you get in ?
That 's not going to happen .
The Delta Lambdas are the biggest bunch of fucking ...
Hey . I 'm pledging Delta Lambda , thank you .
Oh , my God .
Who 's that ?
Dewey ?
Hey .
- What are you doing here ? - Ah .
- Oh , I was worried about you . - Yeah ?
I heard about what happened and I was on the next plane .
- Oh . - Can we talk ?
Yeah . Yeah .
Are you okay ?
I 'm fine , Dewey , or I was .
I mean , things were okay until now .
But , theatre 's going great .
I got my first starring role . We open in two days .
- That is great . - Yeah . I 'm loving it .
You know , and I 've got some great friends ,
and , I 'm seeing someone .
Nice guy . Premed . No apparent psychotic tendencies .
I was just worried .
Look , Sid , if there is some freaked-out
psycho trying to follow ...
in Billy Loomis 's footsteps , you probably already know him .
Or her , or them .
They 're probably already in your life .
They get off on that .
I just want you to be careful , Sid .
Oh , you ... You think I don 't know that , Dewey ?
But what am I supposed to do ?
Just cut everybody off ? Crawl under a rock ? What ?
Just watch out . Keep an eye out .
I 'm going to talk to Chief Hartley and the local police .
I 'm going to just hang around .
I wanna make sure you 're safe , if that 's all right with you .
Yeah . I 'd be honoured .
All right , Sid .
Hey .
- You okay ? - Huh .
- Who was that guy ? - An old friend .
Deputy Dewey , Woodsboro 's finest . What 's he doing here ?
He 's worried . Our surrogate big brother .
Nothing like a funeral to bring a family together .
I 'm going to go say hi .
Chief Hartley said the girl was stabbed seven ... Drop it .
Hello , Sidney .
- How are you ? - Hi . What do you want , Gale ?
Well , I was hoping I might get just a few words with you .
- Cotton . - Hi , Sidney .
Here we are at Windsor College , where Sidney Prescott ...
has just been reunited with Cotton Weary for the first time ...
since she wrongly accused him of murdering her mother .
- What the hell are you doing ? - We want to know how you feel .
Tell us everything that 's happened ,
looking back on the last two years .
Sidney , I 'd just like to say that I forgive and forget ,
and just like you , I 'd like to get back on with my own life .
- Do you have any comments ? - You bitch .
Ah-ah .
Deep breaths . Lot of deep breaths .
Oh , Sidney , share with us , please .
- I 'll share with you . - Okay , okay , okay .
Did you get that on film ?
Yes , I got that on film .
Sid ? Wait , wait , wait , wait , wait .
Where 's she going , Gale ? Sidney ?
Where 's she going ?
Gale , I thought we had an official interview . What 's going on ?
- She didn 't know ? - Man , that was cold .
Hey , you need to check your conscience at the door , sweetie .
I 'm not here to be loved .
Gale , you promised me ten minutes of national coverage .
You 'll get your ten minutes when I get my goddamn interview .
Don 't walk away from me , Gale . I 'm still ...
Gale , I did my part .
Joel .
Dewey .
What are you doing here ?
Why don 't you just leave her alone ?
Hasn 't she been through enough ?
And my name is Dwight .
I was just doing my job , Dwight .
No matter who gets hurt in the process ?
Hey . Who got punched here ... again ?
Well , I don 't condone violence , but maybe you deserved it .
" Deputy Dewey filled the room ...
with his Barney Fife-ish presence . "
You read my book .
Oh , yes , I do read , Miss Weathers .
Oh , Dewey , don 't take it so seriously .
It 's a character in a book .
Page 41 :
" Deputy Dewey oozed with inexperience . "
Don 't you think you 're overreacting just a little bit ?
No . What I think is that you 're a money-hungry ,
fame-seeking and , forgive me for saying ,
mediocre writer who 's got a cold storage
shed where her heart should be .
No offence intended .
Dewey , I never meant to imply ...
How do you know that my dimwitted inexperience ...
isn 't merely a subtle form of manipulation
used to lower people 's expectations ,
thereby enhancing my ability to effectively
manoeuvre within any given situation ?
I 'm sorry .
I don 't know what else to say ...
except I 'm sorry .
No . I 'm the one that 's sorry .
I misjudged you .
Now , if you 'll excuse me , I have some oozing to do .
One more thing .
Nice streaks .
Well .
Hey , I am not a sorority pusher .
I just think , despite its trivialities ,
it is a life-affirming , mentally
stable , healthy environment for you .
I mean , look at this place .
I think you 're taking your psych major
a little too seriously , Hallie .
I 'm fine .
Yeah ? That 's beginning to become your theme song .
" I 'm fine . " Yeah ... Fucked up , insecure , neurotic and emotional .
Sidney , you made it .
Hi . No , I really mean that .
- Hi . - Hi .
Do you girls want a drink ?
Well , actually , yeah , but you know what ? We 'll get it ourselves .
I love those guys . Are they still together ?
I haven 't seen it in , like , three weeks .
- No , they broke up again . - Really ?
Sarah found out that Bailey slept with Gwen .
She dumped him , like , two episodes ago .
I wish she 'd get her shit together .
Hold on . Someone 's calling .
Omega Beta Zeta .
Hello ?
- Yes ? - Who is this ?
- Cici . Who 's this ? - Who do you think ?
Ted ? Where are you ?
Are you drinking ? Hold on .
Ted 's on the other line . He sounds drunk . I 'll call you back .
That shit only calls you when he 's drunk .
- Don 't go over there , Cici . - All right . I 'll call you back .
Okay , Ted . You sound loaded . What 's up ?
Who 's Ted ?
Oh , I 'm sorry . My bad .
I thought you were someone else .
That 's okay . I am .
Who are you calling for ? Nobody 's here .
Where is everybody ?
We 're cosponsoring the acid rain mixer at Phi Gamma Alpha tonight .
- Why aren 't you there ? - I 'm " sober sister . "
I need to be here in case a drunk sister calls and needs a ride .
That 's too bad .
" Drink with your brain . " That 's our motto .
- Who are you calling for ? - What if I said you ?
- What if I said goodbye ? - Why would you want to do that ?
Why do you always answer a question with a question ?
I 'm inquisitive .
Yeah , and I 'm impatient . Do you want
to leave a message for someone ?
Do you want to die tonight , Cici ?
Omega Beta Zeta .
So , was it Teddy ?
No . It was some creep asshole trying to scare me .
That movie Stab is bringing out the crazies .
- Shit . - What is it ?
- I heard a noise . - Where ?
Upstairs .
Shit .
Hello ? Hello ?
Kill , kill , kill , kill , kill , kill .
- Die , die , die , die , die . - Stop it .
I can 't believe you 're alone in that house .
I don 't think I 'm alone .
I 'm out of here .
You 're breaking up . Where are you ?
- Outside . - Don 't panic , Cici .
- Call campus security . - Okay .
Campus Security .
Hi . I 'm calling from the omega Beta ...
I can 't hear you . Hello ?
Hello ?
- Can you hear me now ? - Hello ?
Hello ? Shit .
- Campus Security . - Yes . I 'm calling from ...
I can 't hear you . Hello ?
I 'm calling from the omega Beta Zeta house .
Look , someone is harassing me .
Hello ? Shit .
Hey .
- Jesus , Dawnie , you scared me . - I 'm sorry . I 'm sorry .
Did anyone call for me ?
- What are you doing here ? - I live here , remember ?
I just thought you were going to the mixer .
Yeah , I am . I had to change , so I 'll be out of here now .
Omega Beta Zeta .
- Is Cici there ? - Who 's calling ?
It 's Ted .
It 's your ill-conceived boyfriend .
Okay , so , I 'll see you later .
And don 't forget to set the alarm .
Bye .
Hello , Ted .
You wish it was Ted . Don 't forget to set the alarm .
Hello ?
No . Please , no .
No .
Everyone thinks that sororities are just about blow jobs .
But it 's not true .
We only promote safe , condom sex .
See , we 're about love , respect and responsibility .
Harmonica style is okay , right ?
- Oh , yeah . - Cocktail ?
What took you so long ?
And you know , Derek is a Delta Lambda big brother .
And we like to keep it all in the family .
Wow . You know , you girls have really
given me a lot to think about .
Thanks .
It 's working . It 's working .
- Hey , babe . You wanna dance ? - Oh , I 'd love to ...
with that tall , wide-shouldered fraternity boy .
- Think you can arrange that ? - That hurts .
- Go away . - The Empire Strikes Back .
- Better story , improved effects . - Not a sequel .
Part of a trilogy . Completely planned .
I like those little furry things .
They 're Ewoks . They blow .
Hey .
- How ya doing ? - Good .
- Twits being nice to you ? - Painfully nice .
I take it you will not be pledging Delta Lambda Zeta .
I think not .
- I 'm crushed . - Hey , guys .
Something is up at omega Beta Zeta .
- Police are everywhere . - Hurry .
Come on , let 's go .
- Way to break up the party . - Shit .
I should have brought my drink .
Death by blunt trauma , and there 's a double stabbing .
So it 's definitely not suicide .
Okay . Thank you .
Gale , hi . You 're just getting here . It 's not good .
It 's a single victim . Sorority girl .
So ... I got to go . I 've got a deadline .
- Joel , let 's go . - In-In a minute .
It 's happening again , isn 't it ?
You 'd love that , wouldn 't you ?
Please , stay back .
Better hurry , Gale . Might get scooped .
Come on , I 'm just trying to get close enough to get a shot .
Move it , Joel .
Gale , I have to be honest with you . I 'm not cut out for this .
I mean , I was brought here to do an
interview , not Faces of Death 14 .
Do not fuck with me .
Come on . Get your jacket .
Let 's get you home .
Yeah .
You about ready ?
Almost .
- Hello ? - Hello , Sidney .
Remember me ?
- What do you want ? - I want you . It 's show time .
Then why don 't you show your face , you fucking coward .
My pleasure .
Derek .
Sid ? Sid ?
Sid ?
Sid .
It 's me . It 's me .
- You okay ? You okay ? - Yeah . Yeah .
No , Derek . Don 't .
Sid .
Dewey .
The killer 's in there . And Derek .
- You all right ? - He went that way .
Sidney , he 's in here .
Is everything okay ?
He got me . He got me .
- Now , apply pressure to it . - Don 't do that ...
The police are on their way .
Thanks for your cooperation .
Hallie , I 'll be with you in a few minutes , okay ?
No problem .
That 's the easiest interrogation of my crime-filled life .
I 'm going to go get a quick cup of coffee . You want ?
No .
You want some , Sid ?
How you doing ? You all right ?
Not at all .
You know , I knew this was coming .
- I knew this wasn 't over . - You are not alone , Sid .
Okay ? We are all here for you .
All right ? Whatever you need .
- That poor girl . - I know .
It 's crazy , but ...
Derek could 've been killed , you know .
But he wasn 't .
He 's fine .
He just needs to realise the ' 90s is no time to play hero .
Why would anyone go back in that house anyway ?
I went around to the back of the house and ran into Sid there .
That 's when she told me the killer was inside , so I went in to see .
You 're lucky there 's no nerve damage .
You 're going to have to take it easy though .
So then you went back inside the house ? Yeah .
No struggle ? He just cut you and ran away ?
- You 're lucky he didn 't kill you . - Yeah , it 's awfully convenient .
- Say what ? - Nothing .
It 's just a shame he got away so easily .
It 's just a shame you got there too late ,
right after he disappeared .
Yeah , it is .
We got three victims .
Maureen Evans , Phil Stevens ...
and Cici Cooper .
- Is Cici the girl 's real name ? - Oh , no .
It 's , Casey . Casey Cooper .
As in Casey Becker ?
Excuse me ?
She was a young victim in Woodsboro .
As well as her boyfriend , Steven Orth .
As in Phil Stevens .
Maureen Evans ... Maureen Prescott . That 's Sidney 's mother .
Do you think someone 's trying to duplicate Woodsboro ?
It looks like it .
I think you have a copycat on your hands , Chief .
Jesus Christ .
What are you doing to keep Sidney safe ?
I got my two best detectives guarding her .
Do these guys have to follow you around everywhere ?
Oh . We 're attached at the hip .
How am I ever going to get you alone ?
You know , to be honest , Derek ,
I think it would probably be in your best interest to ...
stay as far away from me as possible .
I hope that was an off-the-cuff remark ...
that holds no subtext whatsoever .
No , actually . I mean it .
I mean , look at you . You already got hurt .
I don 't want to see that happen again .
I 'll take my chances .
Derek , I 'm serious .
This is serious .
You are concerned with my personal well-being and ...
not with trusting me or anything , right ?
Like I said , I just don 't want to see you get hurt .
And I don 't want to see you get hurt .
Okay , Sid ?
- Take care , Miss Weathers . - All right .
- Dewey . - Chief .
Hi .
So , I 'm heading over to admissions to do some leg work . You game ?
I 'm not here to write a book , Miss Weathers .
I 'm here to help Sid .
I want to help her , too .
And help myself , of course .
Come on , Dewey . Smile just once . Please ?
I 'll smile when I catch the killer .
Gale , hi . So who do you think did it ?
What about Sidney 's father ? Has he been ruled out as a suspect ?
Well , he 's supposedly out of the country on business ,
but that sounds a little fishy , don 't you think ?
I 'm not here to do your job , Miss Salt .
What about this ex-cop , Dewey ?
Kind of strange that he showed up .
Yeah , what 's he doing here ?
Dewey 's a good guy , unlike some of us .
Really ?
Well , it just seems that if the killer
is repeating what happened in Woodsboro ,
it 's quite possible that the killer
could be from Woodsboro , that 's all .
Derek , you think Sid will let me interview her for my documentary ?
Oh , yeah . You know , she turned down
Primetime Live , 20 / 20 and Dateline .
- But for you , yeah . - Drop it .
I 've been thinking about this whole murder thing .
- Have they checked out Randy ? - What ?
I know he 's an innocent victim the first
time around , but he 's a little off .
You know what I 'm saying ?
Come on . Randy ? The guy 's harmless .
That 's what they said about Dahmer .
Guys , keep it down .
Come on . What 's up , Sid ?
- Hey , Sid . - How 's it going ?
Where are the Secret Service guys ?
Over there .
And which one is Kevin Costner ?
The one on the right is officer Richards .
He is a Capricorn . Divorced . Father of two .
The one on the left is Officer Andrews . He is a Gemini .
He 's single , but I think he 's gay .
Really ?
Derek ? Penny for your thoughts .
" This morning , I woke up with this feeling ...
I didn 't know how to deal with . "
" And so I just decided to myself ,
I 'd hide it to myself . "
What is he doing ?
Tom Cruise , Top Gun , 1986 .
Derek , don 't .
♪ When you walked into the room ♪
- ♪ I think I love you ♪
- Don 't do this .
♪ I think I love you isn 't that what life is made of ♪
♪ And though it worries me to say ♪
♪ I 've never felt this way , hey ♪
♪ I think I love you so what am I so afraid of ♪
♪ I 'm afraid that I 'm not sure of a love there is no cure for ♪
♪ I think I love you isn 't that what life is made of ♪
♪ And though it worries me to say ♪
♪ I 've never felt this way ♪
♪ Believe me you really don 't have to worry ♪
♪ I only wanna make you happy ♪
♪ And if you say " hey , go away " ♪
♪ I will but I think better still ♪
♪ I better stick around and love you ♪
♪ Do you think I have a case let me ask you to your face ♪
♪ Do you really love me because I think ♪
♪ I love you ♪
Let 's show a little love , huh ?
Come on . Come here , come here .
Don 't worry , Sid . I know things are a little crazy .
Isn 't that a big frat faux pas ?
Oh , yeah . That is a big no-no .
See , you 're not supposed to give your Greek letters to your girl ...
no shape , way or form .
The brothers are going to kick his ass , but it 's tradition .
- It 's tradition . - It 's good luck .
It 'll protect you .
So , tell us about this part you 're getting rave reviews for .
Well , I play this young girl , Sidney Prescott ,
who discovers that her boyfriend is this crazy serial killer ...
who also killed her mother the year before that .
So what kind of research did you do for the part ?
I don 't get it . They get Tori Spelling to play Sid ,
and they cast Joe Blow Nobody to play me .
At least you get David Schwimmer .
I get the guy who drove Jane Seymour 's stagecoach ...
for one episode of Doctor Quinn .
This is Tori Spelling starring in the new film Stab .
Billy , you scared me .
What are you doing here ?
They let me go , Sid . I didn 't do it .
- I 'm innocent . - I know .
- Please . - Why won 't you let me touch you ?
Look , I 've been going through a lot
lately , Billy . And with my mum ...
Sid , I think you need to just deal with that and move on .
I mean , when my mum left my dad , I accepted it .
That 's the way the cookie crumbles . Mums leave .
Yeah , your mum left town . She 's not
buried in a cemetery somewhere .
My mum 's dead , and she 's never coming back . Ever .
- Stupid . - Ooh , I love scary movies .
I 'll wait for video . Okay , let 's get down to business .
The way I see it , someone 's out to make a sequel .
You know , cash in on all the movie murder hoopla .
So it 's our job to observe the rules of the sequel .
The body count is always bigger .
The death scenes are always more
elaborate ... more blood , more gore .
Carnage candy . Your core audience just expects it .
If you want your sequel to become a franchise , never ever ...
How do we find the killer , Randy ? That 's what I wanna know .
Oh . Let 's look at the suspects .
There 's Derek , the obvious boyfriend . Hello , Billy Loomis .
The guy 's premed , and his pity-me surface wound ...
conveniently missed every major vein and artery .
- So you think it 's Derek ? - Not so fast .
Let 's assume the killer , or ' ers , has a half a brain .
He 's not a Nick At Nite rerun type of guy .
He wants to break some new ground .
- Right ? So forget the boyfriend . - Right .
- It 's tired . Who else do we got ? - There 's ...
Mickey , the freaky Tarantino film student .
But if he 's a suspect , so am I. So , let 's move on .
Whoa , wait a ... Let 's not move on .
Maybe you are a suspect .
Well , if I 'm a suspect , you 're a suspect .
You have a point .
- Okay , let 's move on to ... - Hallie .
- Sid 's room-mate ? - Huh .
Serial killers are typically white males .
That 's why it 's perfect . It 's sort of
against the rules , but not really .
Mrs Voorhees was a terrific serial killer .
And there 's always room for Candyman 's daughter .
She 's sweet . She 's deadly . She 's bad for your teeth .
Come on , Randy . These kids are your friends .
Who do you think 's the killer ?
- How about Gale Weathers ? - Gale ? A killer ?
- Why not ? - Well , she is vicious enough .
- She 's an opportunist . - Yeah .
Isn 't it conceivable she 's planning her next book ?
That 's what reporters do , Dewey . They stage the news .
No . Gale 's a lot of things , but Gale 's not a killer .
Just because you 're sweet on her ...
No , I 'm not .
Please , this is me talking . Randy ,
the unrequited love-slave of Sidney Prescott .
I know all about obsession ...
and pain .
You 've got your love scar to prove it .
And so do you .
And what 's with that limp anyway ?
Because you were stabbed in the back .
Severed nerve . Look , Gale 's no killer .
Okay , okay . Whatever you say .
But if she 's not a killer , she 's a target .
Joel , let 's get some establishing shots .
Gale , can we talk for a sec ?
What is it ?
Look , I 'm a little confused here .
I mean , with your given track record ,
why would you wanna be here when the killer strikes again ?
I mean , granted , I should 've read your book before I took this job .
But I 'm reading it now , and ... Whoo .
I read what happened to your last cameraman .
The guy got gutted . Now , me ,
I 'm going to do what any rational human being would do ,
which is get the fuck out of here .
First of all , he wasn 't gutted . I
made that up . His throat was slashed .
What are you ... Gale , gutted , slashed ...
The guy ain 't in the union no more .
It 's a job , Joel .
And like every job , there 's a few drawbacks .
But you 're a professional cameraman .
You 've got to act like one .
Yeah , but I wanna report the news . I don 't wanna be the news .
Besides , brothers don 't last long in situations like this .
This is national television . Think about it .
This is a big chance for you .
The story is monumental . Don 't you wanna be a part of that ?
Come on .
I need you . I cannot do this without you .
Good . Come on .
- Let 's get some work done . - Yeah , let 's go get killed .
We 've been through this before . You know what
I think about your potential as an actress .
I know . I know .
It 's just that with , the murders ...
and the movie and my life ...
I do know how difficult it is for you .
Gus , I just ... I don 't think I can do it .
The battle for the soul is fought in the forum of art .
You 're a fighter , Sid . That 's why you 're
here . That 's why this is your major .
- Yeah , I 'm a fighter . - I didn 't hear that .
- I 'm a fighter . - I don 't believe you .
I don 't .
I 'm a fighter .
Okay .
So , at the risk of sounding like a college drama teacher ,
if you 've got pain around this kind of material , use it .
This is your role , Sid .
Cassandra is one of the great tragic visionaries of literature .
The wars ,
the murder , the madness .
She knew she was cursed .
It was her fate , and she embraced it .
None of us can avoid our fate , but as an artist ...
you can honestly face it ...
and fight it .
You 're good .
There 's no understudy . I 'm desperate .
You can do this .
Okay , everybody . Gather around . Third Act , one last time .
Cue the music .
All , behold the dreaded fate of Troy ...
that once stood proud and light upon the hills of Sparta .
Now shrouded in the deathly smoke of ruin ,
her royal children pitched from her walls ,
her people driven through her ruins .
And now alone in fate 's cruel isolation ...
stands Cassandra ,
her kingdom , family and friends ...
driven to the wind .
No crime against gods or man ...
have I committed ,
save to speak the truth .
And each hideous vision born from my mind ...
has come to pass .
Troy has fallen ,
not by my hand or wish ,
but as I foresaw .
So now , fate 's vengeful eye ...
is fixed ...
on me :
Tell us , o Cassandra , where has the sweetness ...
of life gone ?
What stays fate 's hand from striking now at thee ?
What stays fate 's hand from thee ?
All right , hold it . Hold it .
Everyone , take five .
Sidney ?
Sid . Your escort has arrived .
Derek , how long have you been here ?
I just got here .
Is everything okay ? What 's going on ?
What happened to Mickey ?
We swapped . He had to edit . You get me instead . What happened ?
Derek , don 't .
Don 't . I just need to be alone right now , okay ?
Being alone is not the answer , Sid .
Yeah , well , I think it is .
I need some distance .
Well , do I get a say in this ?
No .
I guess I 'm supposed to be ... understanding .
Yeah .
You got it .
All right . Let 's just assume the killer is repeating Woodsboro ...
Yes ?
- I have Bob calling . - I 'll have to call you back .
That doesn 't explain Sidney 's attack .
Sidney wasn 't killed in Woodsboro .
Wasn 't for a lack of trying .
The killer 's trying to finish what was started .
- Sid 's under protection , right ? - Yeah .
What ?
Bob really needs to talk to you ...
Tell Bob I 'll call him back .
When 'd she start smoking ?
Ever since those nude pictures on the internet .
It was just my head . It was Jennifer Aniston 's body .
Anyway , you 're forgetting something .
In Woodsboro , there were more victims before the homestretch ...
Tatum , my cameraman , Himbry ...
Time out . I don 't need to be hearing
about no dead cameramen , all right ?
I 'm warning you guys . I am a verb away from vacating these premises .
I 'm going to get me some coffee , doughnuts , Prozac ,
see if I can find some crack , Special K ... " X " , not Malcolm ...
and I 'll be back when you guys start talking about something ...
a little more Saved By The Bell-ish , all right ?
- He seems a little shaky . - Don 't worry about him .
If the killer is following a pattern ,
maybe we can figure out who 's next .
I wouldn 't follow a killer 's pattern .
We were all involved in Woodsboro . Could be any one of us .
So what do you wanna do , bonehead ? Sit
here , wait and see who drops next ?
Well , I don 't know . " Phonehead . "
Gale 's not here .
I 'm not interrupting anything , am I ?
You three look deep in thought .
Have you ever felt a knife cut through
human flesh and scrape the bone beneath ?
It 's him .
- Who ? - The killer .
He can see us .
- Just keep him on the phone . - What do you want me to say ?
I don 't know . Just keep him talking . Come on , Gale .
- Hi . - What are we doing ?
Look for somebody with a cell phone .
So what 's your favourite scary movie ?
You 'll never find me .
What do you care ? Let them have their fun .
So , What 's up ?
What 's your favourite scary movie ?
Showgirls . Absolutely frightening . What 's yours ?
- What 's your problem ? - Sorry .
Wait . Let me guess . The House On Sorority Row ?
Dorm That Dripped Blood ? Splatter University ?
Graduation Day ? Final Exam ?
- Am I close ? - Closer than you think .
Too slow , geek . Do you want to die ?
Is that the best you can do ? Because
Billy and Stu were much more original .
- Gimme that . - Hey .
- Who 's this ? - Who 's this ?
Gale Weathers , author of The Woodsboro Murders .
Who ?
Come on .
Okay .
He 's got to be around here some place .
He 's just playing with us .
White male suspect ... nine o 'clock .
- My clock or your clock ? - Your clock .
I 'll go around the back .
Why are you even here , Randy ?
You 'll never be the leading man .
Fuck you .
No matter how hard you try , you 'll never be the hero ,
and you 'll never , ever get the girl .
- Wait . - Shit . Sorry .
- Hey , man ... - Wrong guy , dead boy .
Oh , yeah ? Well , let 's redirect a moment , Mr I 'm-So-original .
- What 's she doing ? - I don 't know .
Hey . Ah .
- What just happened ? - What the hell are you doing ?
- A citizen 's arrest ... - Can I help you ?
- Hello ? Hello ? - Sorry . Beg your pardon .
Where 's your innovation ? Why copycat
two high school loser-ass dickheads ?
Stu was a pussy-ass wet rag .
And Billy Loomis ... Billy Loomis . What the fuck .
Jesus . What a rat looking , homo-repressed mama 's boy .
Why not set your goals higher , huh ?
You wanna be one of the big boys ? Huh ?
Manson , Bundy , O.J. , Son ...
Where 's Randy ?
I don 't know . This guy just grabbed me .
- I 'm okay , Mum . - I don 't see him .
Randy .
Ah .
What 's going on ?
Yo , man . Who broke my window ?
Did your computer just freeze ?
You have an instant message , that 's all . Just hit " alt-M . "
Yeah , but I 'm not signed on .
Someone here in the library . All the terminals are connected .
- He 's here . - Shit .
Get here away from the computer . Sid ,
it 's probably just a sick joke .
- May I see your screen , please . - Wait right here .
Yeah .
Psst . Sid , you okay ?
- Cotton . - Can we talk for a sec ?
This , this isn 't a good time .
Come on , Sid . You sent me to prison .
I did over a year for you . You can give me two minutes .
Cotton , I 'm sorry . Every day I 'm sorry .
I don 't know how to apologise any more .
Don 't be sorry . Sorry-schmarry , Sid . I
have the solution to all our problems .
What are you talking about ?
First of all , forget Gale Weathers .
She doesn 't get it . She doesn 't see the story .
She wouldn 't see the story if it
smacked her in the side of the head .
I mean , have you read that book ? Which brings me to my point .
Who calls me out of the blue , but Diane Sawyer .
Believe me , I was as shocked as you are .
She tells me that if you and I go on the air together ,
she will give us the entire hour .
What ?
We 're talking prime time , Sid . You , me and Diane Sawyer .
- Cotton , I can 't . - No , no . Look , Sidney .
If this is about money , it 's not like we 're not getting paid .
There 's $ 10,000 each , not to mention what I 've
got going on the side with the 900 number .
Cotton ...
I know , I know , I know . You don 't like the press .
I know that , and I respect it .
But-But , Sidney ...
It 's Diane Sawyer . Hello ?
She 's a class act . Sidney , this could
be some very , very heavy exposure .
I 'm sorry .
Look , between the movie and the book ...
people know the truth .
Let 's get on with our lives . There 's been
enough exposure . Why would you want any more ?
Why ? I don 't know , Sidney . I don 't know .
Maybe because I fucking deserve a little exposure ?
I mean , come on , Sidney . You dragged my name through the mud .
Everybody thinks I 'm some kind of psycho killer ,
and all I 'm asking for is one fucking Diane Sawyer interview ...
to maybe get my side of the story straight .
Now , I don 't think I 'm being unreasonable in that request .
Do you ? Honestly ?
I 'm ... sorry , Cotton , but no .
You 're sorry .
Yeah , I bet you 're real sorry , Sidney .
Such a good angle , Sidney . Loveable
and fucked-up Sidney Prescott .
Everybody 's favourite little victim .
- Ow . What are you doing ? - Relax .
Put your hands on top of your head .
Shut the fuck up .
Jesus . I 'm not Billy Loomis . You killed him . He 's dead . Remember ?
Run it by me one more time , will ya ?
Why did you attack Sidney Prescott ?
I didn 't ... There was no attack .
We were talking very heatedly .
Miss Prescott and I ...
have a very complicated past .
I didn 't think that was a crime .
- No , but homicide is . - Okay then , book me . Book me .
Okay ? Look .
I don 't know about homicide , but you 've definitely ...
got me for raising my voice in a public library .
We 're dealing with four murders here . You watch your mouth .
That shouldn 't have been Randy .
- It should have been me . - No .
I should call his mother .
Sid , I already made that phone call .
Are you okay ?
Stop treating me like glass , Dewey . I 'm not going to break .
It 's okay to break .
It 's not going to happen .
You better hope your alibi 's airtight .
Could I please remind everyone here that I 'm an innocent man .
Don 't you watch TV ? Current Edition ?
That was a very insightful programme ...
on which it was made abundantly clear that I 'm an innocent man .
So until you find me standing over a
dead body with a knife in my hand ,
I think you better treat me with the rights and privileges ...
accorded to every innocent citizen in this country .
I don 't ... Is there ... Is there some
problem with the word " innocent " ?
I know . It 's a big one . Chief ?
- What 's going on ? - I have to let him go .
- Why ? - We don 't have anything on him .
Sign here .
Gale . Enjoying the show ?
- Cops are funny . - What do you think you 're doing ?
Waiting for my 15 minutes of fame .
You can understand that , can 't you , Gale ?
Don 't do anything stupid , Cotton .
Gale , you were so instrumental in my freedom .
You 're not having character doubts now , are you ?
Sidney , if you change your mind ...
Come on . Take a hike .
Sorry about that .
What a creep .
They 're going to take you somewhere safe , Sid .
Yeah ? Where 's that .
I don 't know , but I 'll be there with you .
We should get going .
We 'll take you by the dorm , and you can pack some things .
We 've issued a campus lock-in this evening .
No one 's allowed out after dark , okay ?
Yeah .
Who 's doing this , Dewey ?
I mean , if not Cotton , then who ?
I don 't know , Sid , but I 'll find him .
Any leads , Gale ? Do you think the killer will come after you ?
How does it feel to be on the other side of the news ?
There 's Cotton . Cotton . Hey .
Are you still a suspect ?
It 's all been a huge misunderstanding .
Have you been officially released ?
Gale . Hang on one second .
How about a photo ? No ? You look great .
How 're you holding up , Gale ?
Must be scary knowing somebody 's out there
waiting , watching , enjoying all this .
- How does that make you feel ? - Look , local woman .
I know that you hold me up as your career template ...
and it gives you some sort of ... charge to challenge me .
But give it a rest .
You 're right . I 'm sorry . It 's my ...
It was the wrong time . I 'm sorry .
What 's going on ?
Whoo , let 's see . For starters , they impounded my van .
It 's now an official crime scene , thanks to you .
Here 's your footage . Enjoy .
See ya . Wouldn 't wanna be ya .
Joel , I need you .
No . No , you need to have your head examined .
I feel bad , Dewey .
I feel really bad .
I never say that because ...
I never feel bad about anything .
But I feel bad now .
Is this just another ...
brilliant Gale Weathers performance ?
There are no cameras here . I just wanna find this fucker .
I really do .
Me too .
Could I give you a hand ?
What 's in here ?
Just some crowd footage that Joel shot .
Hey , wait a minute .
If the killer really is watching and relishing every minute ,
then he 'd be here on these tapes , right ?
- At each crime scene . - It 's worth a look .
It 's definitely worth a look .
This way .
Dubbing room . Editorial .
Video archive .
- It 's locked . - Can you pick it ?
That would be breaking and entering .
No shit .
There 's got to be a VCR around here somewhere .
What 's in there ?
- Now we 're getting somewhere . - Perfect .
Let 's start with this one .
- Sorry . Oh . - Oh .
- Ow . - I 'm sorry .
- Did I hurt you ? - No .
You 're a money-hungry , fame-seeking ...
forgive me for saying ... mediocre writer ...
who 's got a cold storage shed where her heart should be .
- I didn 't mean to imply ... - Listen .
- You 're cute when you 're angry . - I was rude .
I was being rude .
Dewey , I 'm sorry .
I never meant to hurt you . Hey .
Really .
I should be studying . You know I got a Bio ...
Dewey .
- Sorry . - That 's not my footage .
Outside .
Fuck you .
No matter how hard you try , you 'll never be the hero ,
and you 'll never , ever get the girl .
- Sorry . - Wrong guy , dead boy .
- Stay here . - Dewey , don 't .
Dewey .
There 's no one there .
Fuck .
Gale .
Gale ?
No .
So .
Listen , Sid .
Hey , wait up .
- She 's ... She 's fine . - I 'm her therapist .
Bye , Derek .
Bye .
We better get going .
When this is all over ,
I 'll still be here .
You . Prepare to die .
- You gave up your letters . - Oh , man .
I 'm not ... Guys ...
- To Troy . We march . - Whoo .
This is so romantic .
And so Greek .
Who do you love , baby ?
Sidney .
Did you say " my omega Kappa Beta brothers " ?
No , I said Sidney .
So , where are you taking us , anyway ?
If we tell you , we 'll have to kill you .
Don 't ask ; don 't tell .
Help me .
Oh , my God .
Out of the car , you fucker .
Get down back there . Pull over , you son-of-a-bitch .
I 'll blow your fucking head ...
- Is he dead ? - I don 't think so .
- He 's still breathing . - Oh .
Oh , is he dead ?
Oh , God . I think so .
How are you supposed to get out of here ?
We 're not . It 's a cop car .
Hallie , it 's the only way out . Help me out .
Come on .
We 're jammed up against a pole .
Oh , my God .
Oh . Oh , my God .
No , Sid . Don 't , Sid .
God , I hate this shit .
Oh , my God . Don 't do that again .
Try the window .
Shit .
Get me the fuck out of here , Sid .
I can 't . The door 's jammed . You have to go through the front .
- Oh , no fucking way . - Hallie , do it .
Go on . Hallie , go .
Okay .
Okay , that 's right .
Okay . Okay , that 's good .
Oh , right through his eye .
Come on .
That 's good . Easy . Easy .
He 's not going to hurt you .
Come on . Let 's go . Let 's go .
- Hallie . - What ?
I wanna know who it is .
Oh , no . Come on , Sid . Let 's just go .
I 'm going back .
Look , look . Stupid people go back .
Smart people run . We 're smart people , so
we should just get the fuck out of here .
Hallie , I 'm sick of running .
If we know who it is , then it 's over .
No , we can just get the police .
And when we come back , he 'll be gone . It 'll only take a minute .
- I have to do this . - Sid . No , Sid . Come back .
Sid , come back . Shit .
- Oh , shit . - What ?
- He 's gone . - What ?
No .
Gale .
No , no . This isn 't what it looks like .
Get away from me .
I found Dewey . I tried to help him . I ... No , no . Gale , wait .
Gale . Gale , wait . Gale .
Shit .
- You can 't miss the street ... - Help me .
- Curfew in full effect . - Give me the goddamn phone .
I was right in the middle of a story .
I 've got your goddamn story .
What 's the matter ?
Operator , this is an emergency . Get me the police .
What 's happening ?
The killer . It 's Cotton-fucking-Weary .
Cotton Weary ?
Hello ?
Gus ?
Hello ...
Derek ?
Oh , God .
Derek . Oh , God .
Thank you . Thank God , Sid . Thought I was
going to be up there till opening night .
Shit . Who tied these ? We got to get out of here .
The brothers got me , Sid .
He 's out there . He killed Hallie .
What are you talking about ?
- The killer . He 's here . - Where ?
Right here .
- You 're fast , Sid . - Get me down . Hurry .
I wouldn 't do that if I were you . You
really wanna trust your boyfriend ?
Don 't you know history repeats itself ?
Sid ?
Mickey .
Surprise , Sidney .
What the fuck ?
Since Derek here disappeared on my ass ,
I been on my own all fucking night .
- Thanks a lot , partner . - You motherfucker .
Sid , he 's crazy . You know me better than that .
Come on , Sid . I got to have a partner .
I couldn 't have possibly done this alone .
- God , Derek . - Sid .
Oh , no , Sid . Sid . No , no , no , no .
It 's okay , Derek . We got her .
You ... Sid , he 's lying .
Sid . Sid . Untie me .
Sid , untie me .
Boyfriend . Killer . Boyfriend . Killer .
Sid , the man is lying . Untie me . Sid .
Untie me . Untie me .
What do you think , Derek ? Sidney experiencing some deja vu ?
No . No . I am going to fucking kill you .
Fucking kill you . You are dead . Dead .
Derek .
- Sid . - Derek .
I 'm sorry .
I never ...
would 've ... hurt you .
Never .
No .
You should really deal with your trust issues , Sid .
I mean , poor Derek . He 's completely
innocent . And such a nice boy too .
He 's bright and funny and handsome . Decent
singing voice . And he was going to be a doctor .
This was just the kind of boy you 'd like to take home to Mum .
- If you had a mum . - Fuck you .
Oh . So vulgar . Did Billy let you talk to him this way ?
Billy was a sick fuck , just like you .
No . Billy was a sick fuck who tried to get away with it .
Mickey is a sick fuck who wants to get caught . Yeah .
See , I 've got my whole defence planned out .
I 'm going to blame the movies .
Pretty cool , huh ? It hasn 't been done before .
You see , this is just the beginning , a prelude to the trial .
That 's where the real fun is because
these days it 's all about the trial .
Can 't you see it ? The effects of cinema violence on society .
I 'll get Dershowitz or Cochran to represent me .
Bob Dole on the witness stand in my defence .
Hell , the Christian Coalition 'll pay my legal fees .
It 's airtight , Sid .
I 'm an innocent victim .
- You 're a psychotic . - Yeah , well .
That 'll be our little secret .
Because people love a good trial . It 's
like theatre . They 're dying for it .
And I 've worked hard to give the audience what they want .
That 's what Billy was good at . He
knew ... it 's all about ... execution .
Yeah ? Well , you 're forgetting one thing about Billy Loomis .
What 's that ?
I fucking killed him .
You piece of shit .
Sid .
You got a Linda Hamilton thing going .
No , no . It 's nice . I like it .
Now , who 's doing that ?
Could that be ... the mystery guest waiting in the wings ?
Told ya I had a partner .
Surprise cameo just for you .
Gale .
Mrs Loomis ?
- What ? - Billy 's mother .
Nice twist , huh ? Didn 't see it coming , did ya ?
Jesus .
It can 't be . I 've seen pictures of you .
This is 60 pounds and a lot of work later .
It 's called a make-over . You should try it .
Look a little tired yourself there , Gale .
- So you two are in this together ? - Yeah , well .
Had to have financing . Tuition 's expensive .
Deb , there ... my backer . We met on the Internet .
Psycho Web site . Classifieds .
There 's only an estimated 97 active
serial killers in the country .
So Mickey , here , was quite a find . Definitely one on the way up .
All he needed was a little guidance and nurturing .
As only a mother can do .
Told you it was going to work . Wait till the trial .
It is going to rock .
Oh , Mickey . There 's not going to be a trial .
Gale .
Two birds , one stone .
Oh , Mickey was a good boy , but , my God ,
that whole blame-the-movies motive .
Did you buy that for one second ?
Poor boy was completely out of his mind .
- And you 're not ? - No . I 'm very sane .
My motive isn 't as ' 90s as Mickey 's .
Mine is just good , old-fashioned revenge .
You killed my son .
And now I kill you . And I can 't think of anything more rational .
You 're never going to get away with this .
Of course I will .
Everything 's traceable back to Mickey .
Including the cop gun he used to kill everybody .
But let 's just suppose that you ...
had gotten hold of the other cop 's gun .
And you chased Mickey . And there was
a big shoot-out and a big scuffle .
And you shot Mickey , killed Mickey dead .
But not before he got off one shot at you .
Okay . So , have I covered everything ?
Are there any questions , any comments ? You know what , though ?
Who give a flying fuck anyway ?
Let them try and track down the second possible killer .
Debbie Salt doesn 't exist .
You 're as crazy as your son was .
What did you just say ?
Was that a negative , disparaging
remark about my son ? About my Billy ?
No , Billy was a good boy .
Billy was perfect . You did a bang-up job , Mrs Loomis .
It 's not wise to patronise a woman with a gun , Sidney .
Randy spoke poorly of Billy , and I got a little knife-happy .
I was a good mother .
You know what makes me sick ?
I 'm sick to death of people saying that it 's all the parents ' fault .
That it all starts with the family . You wanna blame someone ?
Why don 't you blame your mother ?
She 's the one who stole my husband and broke up my family .
And then you took my son .
You don 't know what it is to be a mother .
To raise a child and teach him ... and guide him ...
And abandon him .
Isn 't Mickey supposed to be dead ?
Don 't you fucking move .
- Goddamn it . - Cotton .
Okay , okay , okay . Everybody slow down .
I have had a very , very bad day ,
and I would like to know exactly what the fuck is going on here .
Sidney ?
Cotton , meet Billy Loomis ' mother .
She 's the killer .
What ?
- Then who 's that ? - The other killer .
- Mickey . - Okay .
- Look , Cotton ... - Shut up .
So . Hi .
You 're , not Debbie Salt , are you ?
You 're not with the Post Telegraph .
No , but I can still help you , Cotton .
Ah-ah-ah .
You don 't need her . Let me kill her .
As long as she 's alive , you 're never going to be the lead story .
That 's what you really want , isn 't it , Cotton ?
If you really wanna be in the spotlight ,
just let me kill her ... right now .
Then you 're the only survivor . You 're the star .
She sent you to prison for a year .
Personally , I think it 's rather poetic .
No . No , Cotton , don 't you listen to her .
Oh . Well ...
It 's , quite a predicament you 're in , Sid .
- Cotton ... - I mean , she makes a good point .
Let me think about this .
Maybe you should too .
Betcha that Diane Sawyer interview 's
looking real good right about now .
Huh ?
Consider it done .
Wow .
That ... was intense .
Hey , Sidney ...
Look , I want you to know that I would
never , ever do anything to hurt you .
Cotton , give me the gun .
Yeah . Okay . Sure . Take it .
Hey , Sid , we should talk about exactly what happened here .
You know ... I mean , get our stories
straight for the press statement .
Oh , shit .
Cotton .
Could somebody get me out of here ?
Gale . Are you all right ?
I been shot . Of course not .
- Help . - Give me your hand , Gale .
Jesus , you scared the crap out of me .
Isn 't anybody else down there , is there ?
No .
So much for reporting from the trenches , huh ?
- Shut up , Cotton . - How bad is it ?
Just bounced off my ribs .
Geez , Gale , you got more lives than a cat .
Give me one of those .
Is she dead ?
I don 't know . They always come back .
Whoa .
Just in case .
- That about wraps it up , Chief . - Okay , Frank .
Take it easy . You got a couple broken ribs .
- Greg , I 'm okay . - Sure .
Hey , Gale . Are you all right ?
- Joel . - I 'm back .
You know , I was thinking maybe we could
get the scoop like in the old days .
You 're Gale Weathers ... at Windsor College .
We got a live one here .
Move it .
Where 's Gale ?
There room in that one over there ?
- Yeah . Watch your back . - Dewey .
- Let 's go . - Oh , God .
I can 't believe you 're alive .
- Are you okay ? - Gale .
You hang in there .
Knife went into some old scar tissue .
Saved his life .
Bye-bye .
I 'm coming with you .
- Can you tell us what you saw ? - What happened in there ?
Can you tell us how it feels to be a hero ?
Talk to Cotton . He 's the man you want to interview .
He 's the hero .
Cotton .
What went on in there ? What happened ?
Is it true you 're a hero ?
- Details , please . - Look , guys ,
no one wants to give you the story more than I do .
Unfortunately , there is a time and a place ,
and indeed , a price for everything ,
so feel free to call me .
Come on , Cotton . Tell us something .
Well , I 'll tell you one thing .
It 'll make a hell of a movie . Thank you .
Scream .
Could be your best friend . Could be your enemy .
♪ Life 's river shall rise ♪
♪ She said ♪
♪ And only the strong shall survive , she said ♪
♪ But I 'm feeling quite weak she said ♪
♪ Will you comfort and forgive me , she said ♪
♪ She said she 's still searching ♪
♪ For salvation 's light ♪
♪ Yet she wishes all day ♪
♪ And then she prays all night ♪
♪ She said she won 't speak of love ♪
♪ Because love she 's never known ♪
♪ Well , it 's moments like these ♪
♪ When she hates to be alone ♪
♪ Forgive me ♪
♪ She said ♪
♪ I 'm sleeping and right in the middle of a good dream ♪
♪ When all at once I wake up from something ♪
♪ That keeps knocking at my brain ♪
♪ Before I go insane I hold my pillow to my head ♪
♪ And spring up in my bed screaming out the words I dread ♪
♪ I think I love you ♪
♪ I think I love you so what am I so afraid of ♪
♪ I 'm afraid that I 'm not sure of a love there is no cure for ♪
♪ I think I love you isn 't that what life is made of ♪
♪ Though it worries me to say that I never felt this way , yeah ♪
♪ Believe me , you really don 't have to worry ♪
♪ I only wanna make you happy and if you say hey , go away , I will ♪
♪ But I think better still I 'd better stay around and love you ♪
♪ Do you think I have a case let me ask you to your face ♪
♪ I think I love you ♪
♪ Yeah , I think I love you so what am I so afraid of ♪
♪ Afraid that I 'm not sure of a love there is no cure for ♪
♪ I think I love you isn 't that what life is made of ♪
♪ Though it worries me to say that I never felt this way , yeah ♪
♪ I don 't know what I 'm up against , I don 't know what it 's all about ♪
♪ I got so much to think about yeah ♪
♪ Yeah , I think I love you so what am I so afraid of ♪
♪ I 'm afraid that I 'm not sure of a love there is no cure for ♪
♪ Do you think you love me ♪
♪ I think I love you ♪
♪ Pain goes away I dig a hole ♪
♪ When it goes away I 'll dig a hole ♪
♪ Running , going out at night ♪
♪ Friends they push and pull you ♪
♪ Burned out ground poor flowers ♪
♪ Spinning , falling out of time ♪
♪ When it goes away I 'll dig a hole ♪
♪ Ia-la-la-la , ooh ♪
♪ I 'll dig a hole ♪
♪ When it goes away ♪
♪ I 'm reminded ♪
♪ Someone thought they knew me ♪
♪ That I hadn 't changed at all ♪
♪ Wrapped up in a picture perfect package ♪
♪ That just stands up way too tall ♪
♪ Because they see my world ♪
♪ Ooh , through the eyes of sand ♪
♪ You walk in desert , baby , you 're a polished stone ♪
♪ Ooh , oh ♪
♪ You don 't know my world ♪
♪ Ah-ah ♪
♪ You walk in the desert ♪
♪ And I walk in the desert ♪
♪ Yeah , I walk in the desert ♪
Scream .
Could be your best friend . Could be your enemy .
♪ Scream I hear him coming ♪
♪ I see him coming I hear him coming , peace ♪
♪ You all be tripping man , the ghetto got me I know it ♪
♪ I be like eyes open , turning with both of my toys on him ♪
♪ These daydreams sometimes turn to nightmares ♪
♪ I be trying to shake it but it seem to be like right there ♪
♪ I know some homies who made deals for a short time to live good ♪
♪ But when its all over you should see ♪
♪ The data that 'll put them out the hood ♪
♪ One , two I 'm coming for you ♪
♪ Three , four I 'm kicking up in your door ♪
♪ This whole life it seem to be a bad dream ♪
♪ Scream as loud as you want but ain 't ♪
♪ Nobody going to hear your scream ♪
♪ Scream I hear him coming ♪
♪ I see him coming I hear him coming ♪